So…
所以
So you just came to my place?
你就毫不猶豫來我這裡了嗎
Yes, though I don't want to.
對 雖然不情願…
Geez.
真是的
Kazuma, why don't you just stay out of this?
和真你不多管閒事會死嗎
I will help you because I have no other choice.
因為逼不得已 我會協助你
But you can't boss me around anymore.
但你不能再對我指手畫腳了
Gosh, I can't stand you.
真是的 真受不了你
Yeah.
就是說啊
No more calling us troublemakers.
你以後不能再叫我們麻煩製造者了
After all, we're companions.
畢竟我們是夥伴
Of course, I'll help you, I won't leave you to die.
當然會協助你 不會見死不救
You, the crazy magician.
腦袋有問題的魔法師
You are not going to blow up my house
妳該不會又想像上次那樣
like you did the last time, are you?
把我的房子炸掉吧
Say what?
你說什麼
But…
不過…
It really hurts my heart
如果你們是聽信 街頭巷尾的不好謠言
if you believe those bad rumors
懷疑我的人品的話
and do not trust me.
還真是令人心寒呢
T-This is just part of the investigation.
這…這只不過是調查的一環
Of course, I know, Lady Dustiness.
我當然知道 達斯堤尼斯大人
Please make yourself at home, just stay as long as you like.
請妳別客氣 想待多久就待多久吧
We are allowed to stay as long as we want.
我們得到想待多久 就待多久的許可了
I want to stay in the largest room.
我要住最大的客房
Kazuma, that's not fair!
和真 你太奸詐了
I want the room closest to the dining room.
我要住在離餐廳最近的房間
-I want to live in the room at the top of this house. -Hey, wait a minute.
-我想住這棟房子最頂端的房間 -喂 等一下
Hey, Aqua, what are you doing up here?
喂 阿克婭 妳幹嘛上來啊
-What's the matter, can't I come up? -I am sorry my companion is being so rude.
-怎樣啦 難道我不能上來嗎 -我的夥伴真令人抱歉
-You should all sleep down there together. -Both of you come down now.
-妳們就在下面擠在一起睡吧 -你們兩個都下來啦
It seems you're having a hard time too, Lady Dustiness.
看來達斯堤尼斯大人也很辛苦呢
-I'm sorry. -Maid! Is there a maid here?
-女僕 女僕在嗎 -對不起
I am sorry my companion is being so rude.
我的夥伴真令人抱歉
(Konosuba Season 3)
《為美好的世界獻上祝福！ 第三季》
(Episode 4: Divine Punishment for This Handsome Chivalrous Thief)
(第4集 為帥氣的義賊獻上天譴)
My plan has gone awry.
我的計劃出了差錯
I really want to return to the cozy castle.
好想回到溫暖的城堡
Iris, I will do my best.
愛麗絲 哥哥會加油的
Thieves usually break in at night, do not they?
盜賊要闖空門會挑晚上吧
What is this room for?
這是什麼房間
Hey, it's you!
搞什麼 是你啊
-There's nothing here. -My name is Kazuma.
-我叫和真 -這裡什麼都沒有喔
Keep from wandering around aimlessly.
你可別因為沒事做就到處亂跑喔
What are you looking at?
你在看什麼啊
Hey!
喂
A bathhouse?
澡堂?
Is this a two-way mirror?
這是雙面鏡嗎
Darkness is going to live here,
達克妮絲要住在這裡
so you're here to clean the mirror?
所以你來清潔鏡子嗎
D-Do you want to watch it together?
要…要一起看嗎
How could I have fallen for that?
我怎麼可能上這種話的當啊
Alright, hurry up and get out.
好了 快出去吧
I'll stay in this room.
我要住這間
Wait, you want to stay in this room?
等一下 你要住這間?
Hey, don't get the wrong idea, okay?
喂 你不要亂想好嗎
I am only staying in this room
我只是想保護夥伴
to protect my companions.
才住在這個房間的
Nonsense!
胡說八道
How can I let a little brat like you
怎麼能讓你這種臭小鬼
look at Lalatina's naked body?
欣賞拉拉蒂娜的裸體
Unfortunately,
很遺憾
I've already bathed with Darkness.
我已經和達克妮絲一起泡過澡了
Do you want everyone in the house
你想讓整棟房子的人
to know about this room?
都知道有這個房間嗎
This is a trade!
這是交易
Be a good boy and keep quiet
如果不想被女僕們討厭
if you do not want the maids to despise you.
就給我乖乖閉嘴
Dealing with
對女僕來說
sexual harassment is part of being a maid.
被人性騷擾也是工作的一環
I take it that you want to make a deal with me?
怎麼樣 是你要跟我做交易吧
You always give off a vibe that is like mine.
總覺得你散發出和我同類的味道
Now is the time for us to work together.
這時候應該握手合作吧
Flip.
心動
Sounds interesting, huh?
聽起來很有趣嘛
Tell me exactly what you are talking about.
告訴我你們究竟在說什麼
This guy wants to peep…
這傢伙想偷窺…
(Konosuba) I'm sorry.
對不起
Then three days went by.
後來過了三天
We are happy living at the mansion.
在宅邸的生活很舒適
There are no signs of any cases happening.
也沒有案子要發生的跡象
Oh, you're having lunch too?
咦 你也在吃午餐嗎
Good morning.
早安
It's already past noon now.
現在已經過了中午了
It was on purpose that I stayed up late
我是為了預防盜賊闖入
to keep thieves out.
才故意熬夜的
By the way,
對了
I heard that you stayed up every night
聽說我不在阿克塞爾的期間
while I was away from Axel.
妳也每天都熬夜吧
Um…Well…
這…這個嘛
Your sudden disappearance worried me.
因為你突然被帶走 我很擔心啊
That's not important. Are there signs of thieves breaking in?
這不重要 有盜賊闖入的跡象嗎
What are you panicking about?
妳在慌張什麼啊
I see, you were really worried about me.
原來妳是真的在擔心我啊
I never thought you would be cute sometimes.
沒想到妳也有可愛的地方
You are clearly weak,
你…你明明很弱
but you always manage to get into trouble!
卻擁有常常被扯進麻煩事的體質
And on top of that, you die easily.
而且很容易就死
It is not my desire to be in trouble.
我…我又不是喜歡才被扯進去的
It is also not my choice to die.
也不是想死才死的
What's going on? It's like a romantic comedy.
怎麼回事 好像戀愛喜劇
I would not know what to say
妳突然正經八百說這些
if you suddenly took this so seriously, okay?
我會不知道該怎麼應對好嗎
Kazuma.
和真
Do you want to
你吃完早餐後
go on a date with me after breakfast?
要不要跟我約會呢
Flip.
心動
Explosion!
爆裂魔法
I knew it!
我就知道是這樣
-What's wrong? Is it the Devil King's Army? -That scared me.
-怎麼了 是魔王軍嗎 -嚇我一跳
Sion!
法
-What's that all about? -No!
-那是怎麼回事啊 -討厭
The pesky noise you are making
喂 妳製造的噪音
has already riled up the royal capital's populace.
已經在這個王都引發一片民怨
Seems like I have made quite a name for myself.
看來我聲名大噪了啊
I should have let you learn some advanced magic.
早知道就應該讓妳學些上級魔法
You just said something that can't be ignored, right?
你剛剛說了不能置若罔聞的話吧
Thus and so.
如此這般
Hey.
喂
Don't underestimate the water goddess.
不要小看水之女神啦
Aqua drank all the wine
在這一週內
-in the mansion's cellar in this week. -There's an expensive wine in the study, isn't there?
-書房裡有一瓶昂貴的酒吧 -阿克婭把宅邸的藏酒都喝光了
-Hurry up and bring it here.
-快點把它拿過來
At that moment, my explosion magic detonated.
這時候我的爆裂魔法炸開了
Poor Hans, a leader of Devil King's Army.
可憐的魔王軍幹部漢斯
I blew him to pieces.
被炸成了碎片
Now, let us talk about
接著來說說
-how active I was when I was fighting against Sylvia, -Megumin keeps talking about her heroic deeds every day.
-惠惠每天都在說自己的英勇事蹟 -與魔王軍幹部席薇亞戰鬥時
-who was a leader of Devil King's Army. -As for me…
-至於我呢 -我的表現有多活躍吧
Lady! Lady!
大姊姊 大姊姊
Please give me a massage.
麻煩幫我做那個按摩
Tomorrow, I want to eat sukiyaki made from a giant wild buffalo.
明天我想吃巨型野牛的壽喜燒
Also, the down comforter I ordered has arrived.
然後我之前訂的羽絨被送到了
Please put it in my room.
幫我放在我的房間
L-Lady Dustiness…
達…達斯堤尼斯大人
Um…
那個…
Sorry, although I said before,
是我請你們不用客氣
please make yourself at home…
還說這種話真不好意思…
You don't have to say it.
您不用明講沒關係
(Konosuba) We'll leave right away.
我們馬上就離開
Now that I have slept too much during the day, I am out of sleep.
白天睡太飽了 害我現在睡不著
Let us go for a midnight snack.
去吃宵夜吧
We have to leave here tomorrow.
明天就得離開這裡了啊
Is that Aqua?
是阿克婭嗎
Surprisingly, no one is on guard.
居然沒有半個人看守
Am I overthinking it?
難道是我想太多了嗎
It looks like luck has finally come on the last day.
看來最後一天好運總算降臨了
Goddess of luck, Lady Eris, thank you.
幸運女神艾莉絲大人 感謝您
I just felt like there was someone there.
剛剛好像感覺到奇怪的氣息
Lurk.
潛伏
I am probably overthinking it.
是我多心了吧
The treasure sensor says that the treasure is at…
根據感應寶物 寶物是在…
Over here?
這邊嗎
Caught you!
抓到了
Alright, surrender!
好了 束手就擒吧
This is your toughest opponent yet,
擾亂社會安寧的可惡盜賊
you disgusting thief who is causing chaos.
妳遇到難纏的對手了
I am not like those fools.
我和那些傻瓜不一樣
I once went up against the leaders of Devil King's Army,
妳可別以為能從挑戰過
so do not ever think you can get away from me.
魔王軍幹部的本大爺手中逃走喔
Stop, wait!
住手 等一下
Are you…
你難道是…
What's going on? I recognize this voice.
怎麼回事 這個聲音好耳熟
No way could you be Kazuma, could you?
你該不會是和真吧
The place you are grabbing is a bad one right now.
話說你現在抓著糟糕的地方
What are you talking about? I'm just apprehending an intruder.
哪有 我只是在抓入侵者
It's me!
是我啦
Chris, are you the rumored chivalrous thief?
克莉絲就是傳聞中的義賊嗎
I can't get married now.
我嫁不出去了
What can I do? I thought you were a thief.
有什麼辦法 我以為妳是盜賊
Why are you in this place?
話說你為什麼會在這種地方啊
Is Darkness in this house?
達克妮絲在這棟房子裡嗎
Oh no, this is bad.
糟糕 這下不妙啊
If she finds out I am doing this, she will be furious.
要是她知道我在做這種事會生氣的
If you truly say sorry to her,
只要老實向她道歉
she probably will not kill you.
她應該不至於殺了妳吧
Repent well.
好好贖罪吧
No, that's not it!
等一下 不是啦
There's a reason I'm doing this.
我會這麼做是有原因的
Has he left?
走了嗎
Can't be helped, I'll just tell you the truth.
沒辦法 我就老實跟你說吧
Actually…
其實…
No, I don't want to hear it.
等一下 我不想聽
Why not?
為什麼
I have a feeling it will get me into trouble again.
感覺又會被扯進麻煩事裡
Just like always.
就像往常那樣
But…
可是…
Don't say it!
別說了
Okay, before anyone else comes,
好了 趁還沒有人來之前
hurry up and run away.
快點逃走吧
I'll let you off the hook.
我放妳一馬
No. Um…
不 那個…
I have a favor to ask of you.
我有事想請你幫忙
I don't want to hear it, I don't want to hear it!
我不想聽 我不想聽
And think about it carefully.
而且妳仔細想想喔
The lord known
等一下來這裡的
for being a horny jerk is coming later.
是那個以好色惡名昭彰的領主喔
If he sees that you have been caught,
要是他看到妳被抓到了
he will definitely…
肯定會…
Someone's coming.
好像有什麼聲音
I'll retreat for today.
我今天就先撤退了
I will come back here and explain why.
之後再來跟你解釋原因
There is no need to come anymore.
不用再來了
Rather than that, tie me up.
比起這個 妳把我綁起來
That way, I can claim that you fled.
這樣我才能辯稱是妳逃走了
Got it.
我知道了
Bind.
Bind
I'm off.
那我走了
Are you okay, Kazuma?
和真 你沒事吧
Have you been hit with Bind?
你中了Bind嗎
Where's the thief?
盜賊呢
Unfortunately, I almost caught him.
很遺憾 我差點就能抓到他了
I was really too careless.
我真是太大意了
Hurry up and untie me.
快幫我解開繩子
Did he run away?
對方逃走了嗎
You're not hurt, are you?
你沒受傷吧
What did the thief look like?
盜賊長什麼模樣
Uh…It was a man wearing a suspicious mask.
呃…是戴著可疑面具的男人
It could be someone
搞不好
even stronger than Leaders of Devil King's Army.
是比魔王軍幹部還厲害的傢伙
Th-That strong?
對…對方這麼厲害嗎
Speaking of which, Kazuma,
話說回來 和真
despite your scraggy appearance,
雖然外表像蓑蛾一樣
are you really unable to move right now?
但你現在真的動不了嗎
Isn't that obvious?
一看不就知道了嗎
I chased him right up until the end.
我一直追著他到最後一刻
Stop talking and untie me quickly!
別說了 快幫我解開啦
It's really uncomfortable.
很難受耶
Kazuma.
和真
I know now is not the right time to say this,
雖然現在不該說這個
but I am sorry for something I did.
但有件事我想向你道歉
What is it? Go ahead.
什麼事 妳說吧
I'm telling you.
我跟你說
You did not return
你被帶走之後
after being taken away, right?
不是一直沒有回來嗎
What? Right.
什麼 對啊
I looked around in your room
那時候我為了打發時間
to pass the time at that time.
在你的房間裡到處亂翻
So,
結果
I broke that thing that looked like a doll
你做到一半的那個像是人偶的東西
you were half way through making.
不小心被我玩壞了
This jerk…
這傢伙
It's okay.
沒關係啦 那種東西
I can make a new one.
只要重新再做就好了
Hurry up and release me from this restraint.
快幫我解開束縛
Are you willing to forgive me?
你願意原諒我嗎
Then I might as well say it all now.
那我就趁現在全部說出來吧
Actually, I figured it
其實那時候
would be fine to drink bubble wine there
我想說反正這個房間沒人在用
since nobody was
應該沒關係吧
using the room anyway.
就在那裡喝泡泡酒了
Because, you see, if I drink in my room,
因為啊 如果在自己的房間喝
I will have to clean up the food and empty the bottles,
喝完後要收拾下酒菜和空瓶子
which is a headache.
不是很麻煩嗎
And then I got drunk at that time.
然後我那時候喝醉了
I broke a lot of other things.
還破壞了很多其他東西
Sorry about that.
抱歉啦
Really want to beat her up.
好想揍倒她
I-It's okay.
沒…沒關係啦
After all, we are very good friends.
畢竟我們的交情很好
It was wrong of me not to go back.
是沒有回去的我不好
Alright, let's not talk about that.
好了 別說這些了
Hurry up and untie me.
快幫我解開束縛
This situation is indeed what Aqua described.
這個情況的確跟阿克婭說的一樣
It looks quite interesting.
看樣子好像很有趣
What exactly happened?
到底發生了什麼事
Help!
救救我
Come on, speak up.
來 快點說
Quickly say, "I apologize for being too arrogant lately."
快說對不起 我最近太囂張了
You just keep causing me trouble.
就只會給我添麻煩
Say your apologies quickly.
快說對不起
Quickly say, "Sorry, I embarrassed you."
快說對不起 我讓妳蒙羞了
I'm sorry.
對不起
I'm sorry for causing you trouble.
對不起 給妳添麻煩了
-I'm sorry I've embarrassed you. -Say that again.
-對不起 我讓妳蒙羞了 -我想再聽你說一次那句話
Hurry up, that cool line.
快點 就是那句帥氣的話
How many points?
幾分呢
How many points is my Explosion worth?
我的爆裂魔法是幾分
Don't do this.
別這樣
It only needs to be said once.
那種話只要說一遍就夠了
Come on, tell me.
好嘛 快說啦
Alright, alright.
好啦好啦
Don't be shy, tell me.
別害羞 快說啦
It's very embarrassing.
很丟臉啊
-It is not bad to switch roles every so then. -Quickly save me.
-偶爾立場對調也不錯 -救救我 快救救我
-Alright, go ahead and say it. -Lord Aldarp.
-好了 快說吧 -阿爾達普大人
I see.
原來如此
You were so sure of yourself when you said it,
你說得那麼信心十足
but you failed?
卻失敗了嗎
So, the thief is a powerful thief with a mask?
盜賊是戴著面具的厲害怪盜 是嗎
Yes.
是的
But you can't say it was a total failure.
但也不能說是完全失敗吧
Without me,
要不是有我在
Aldarp would have been in trouble now.
阿爾達普大叔現在也遭殃了
He's just third-rate.
他只不過是三流
So he's a third-rate adventurer.
是三流冒險者啊
These are the words of Mr. Kazuma, who has fought
這是和許多魔王軍幹部交手過的
with many of Leaders of Devil King's Army.
和真先生說的話
Yeah, it seems that chivalrous thief is really something.
是啊 看來那個義賊真的很厲害吧
Wait, Kazuma is…
等等 和真他…
Um…
那個…
Anyway, good job.
不管怎樣 辛苦你了
It is not a failure because you did not catch the chivalrous thief,
你不是因為沒抓到義賊而失敗
but rather a success because you prevented him from stealing.
而是成功地阻止了義賊偷竊
No one can blame you.
任何人都不能責備你
You should be grateful for Princess Iris's mercy.
你要感謝愛麗絲殿下的仁慈
But you have no reason to stay in the city any longer.
但你沒有理由繼續待在城裡
Alright, leave quickly.
好了 快離開吧
The bubble wine in the royal capital
王都的泡泡酒
is not as good as the rumors suggest.
並沒有傳聞中那麼好嘛
It's a souvenir.
這是伴手禮
You've got no sense.
妳真的很不會看氣氛呢
I'm really depressed.
我很沮喪耶
Anyway, you have nothing to do today, right?
反正你今天已經沒事做了吧
This jerk…
這傢伙
The bubble wine sold in Mr. Michael's store
阿克塞爾鎮的麥克先生店裡
in Axel Town is much better.
賣的泡泡酒比這個要好多了
Who is Mr. Michael?
麥克先生是誰啊
The number of your friends in town is growing.
話說妳在鎮上的朋友 慢慢地變多了呢
Long ago, an elderly gentleman expressed his gratitude
前陣子有一個大叔來宅邸
for your assistance in healing his wound
留下高級的肉
by presenting us with a gift of premium meat.
說是感謝妳幫他治好傷口
I have never heard of this before.
我是第一次聽說這件事
I do not recall getting that meat.
我不記得有收到那塊肉
I asked Darkness to cook it.
我請達克妮絲做成料理
The two of us ate it.
兩個人一起吃掉了
-What? -Ouch!
-那算什麼啊 -好痛…
-I didn't get a single bite! -What are you doing, jerk?
-我一口都沒有吃到耶 -妳幹嘛啊 混蛋
-What a coincidence that we have met here. -You're…
-咦 在這種地方遇到真巧呢 -妳就是這點讓人…
Lady Aqua.
阿克婭大人
Who are you?
誰啊
I see that you still like to joke around.
妳還是一樣喜歡開玩笑呢
Lady Aqua.
阿克婭大人
Hey, this guy is really good at pretending to know us.
喂 這個人還真會裝熟耶
Um… it's me.
那…那個 是我啊
The Swordsmanship Master who was granted a Cursed Sword by you…
是被妳賜予魔劍的劍術大師…
It's Mr. Katsuragi, you've seen him before, right?
是葛城先生啦 以前有見過吧
Who's that? I'm Mitsurugi.
那是誰啊 我叫御劍啦
(Konosuba) My name is Mitsurugi.
我叫御劍
Are you familiar with the person whose name is Mitsurugi?
講御劍 妳不知道是誰嗎
It's the wielder of the Cursed Sword…
就是魔劍的持有者啦 魔劍的
You can't be seriously mistaken.
你該不會是真的搞錯了吧
Can you try calling me by my first name?
你能試著叫我的名字嗎
We do not know each other well enough to use our first names.
我們的交情還沒好到能直呼名字
It's Kyouya!
是響夜
Honestly say you don't remember if you do.
如果不記得就老實說
My name is Mitsurugi Kyouya.
我叫御劍響夜
Forget it.
算了
It's not important, Lady Aqua.
這不重要 阿克婭大人
I am so glad that we got to see each other again today.
我很感謝今天能像這樣與妳重逢
What, you want to give it to me?
什麼 你要送我嗎
I came across this on my trip.
這是我在旅途中得到的便宜貨
I am not sure if you would like it.
不知道妳喜不喜歡
So cool, really so cool!
太帥了 實在太帥了
It's really infuriating!
真令人火大
It's too small, I can't wear it.
太小了 我戴不下
(Konosuba) Excuse me, three bubble wine, please.
不好意思 請給我們三杯泡泡酒
Wake up quickly.
快醒醒
Hey, wake up quickly.
喂 快醒醒
Hey, Kazu--
喂 和…
Thief!
有宵小
It's me, it's me.
是我啦 是我
Stop, where are you touching?
住手 你在摸哪裡
Stop. Darkness!
住手 達克妮絲
Darkness, help me!
達克妮絲 救救我
(Konosuba) What? So it's you, Chris.
搞什麼 是克莉絲啊
It's me!
是我啦
You hugged me because you knew it was me, right?
你是確定入侵者是我才抱住的吧
Nocturnal visits a man's room
夜訪男人的房間
and then screams out loud at the slightest touch?
結果一碰妳就大聲尖叫
What kind of seduction method is that?
到底是什麼美人計啊
This is neither a nocturnal visit nor a seduction method.
這才不是夜訪 也不是美人計
I said I would come back
我不是說了嗎
and explain why, didn't I?
會再來跟你解釋原因
Hey. You.
等一下 喂 你
Don't pretend you didn't hear.
不要假裝沒聽到啦
I told you I did not want to hear your reason.
我說過不想聽妳解釋吧
Talk about it next time.
下次再說
To be specific, let's talk about it next year.
具體來說是明年再說
I must explain it now.
一定要現在說才行
Please, listen to me.
拜託你聽我說啦
Listen to me…
聽我說…
Alright, what is it?
好啦 到底是什麼
I am collecting super strong, rare items known as sacred treasure.
我正在收集 叫做神器的超強稀有道具
Sacred treasure?
神器?
Sounds troublesome. I don't want to hear anymore.
感覺好麻煩 我已經不想聽了
Listen to me, please.
聽我說啦
I have heard that adventurers with black hair, eyes,
聽說那個道具只有黑髮黑眼
and a weird name are the only ones who can get that item.
名字很奇怪的冒險者能得到
Names as weird as yours.
跟你一樣奇怪的名字
Don't say my name is weird.
不准說我的名字奇怪
Is not that just the cheat item that reincarnated people receive at the start?
那不就是轉生者一開始 得到的作弊道具嗎
Is Chris looking for that?
克莉絲正在找那個嗎
I heard its effects vary.
聽說效果各有不同
It can grant immense attack power.
能帶來強大的攻擊力
Or bring about great wealth.
或帶來巨大的財富
Wealth…
財富…
So it was you?
原來是妳啊
Sorry, sorry!
抱歉 抱歉
However, sacred treasure is extremely dangerous.
不過神器是很危險的東西
It must be retrieved.
必須收回來才行
Who is going to retrieve it? What's the purpose?
誰要收回? 有什麼目的?
Well…
這個嘛…
To protect my client's privacy,
為了保護委託人的隱私
I can't say anything.
我不能說
Then I'm out of this.
那我不管了
What follows is the important part.
接下來才是重點
Actually, the castle also gives off a powerful aura of treasure.
其實城堡裡也傳來強烈的寶物氣息
It is hardly surprising that the castle houses powerful treasure.
城堡裡有厲害的寶物是理所當然的
Exactly, so I want to ask for your help.
沒錯 所以我想拜託你
See? I knew it. No need to say more.
看吧 我就知道 別說了
I do not wish to get into more trouble.
我不想再被扯進麻煩事裡
You do have night vision, right?
我記得你擁有夜視技能吧
And the skills of lurking and sensing enemies.
還有潛伏和感應敵人技能
Use these skills and come search with me.
你用這些技能和我一起去
Don't make me an accomplice to a crime.
不要讓我成為犯罪的幫凶啦
The bad feeling came true.
不好的預感果然成真了
I am not going to assist you with that.
誰要幫妳做那種事啊
Dude, you are being really icy.
別這麼說嘛 冷漠的傢伙
Scram, scram, go back already.
快滾 快滾 快給我回去
I will use the bind you cast yesterday
要是不回去
to capture and molestation you
我就用昨天妳施展的Bind抓住妳
if you don't go back.
對妳性騷擾
I'll retreat for today then.
我今天就先撤退了
I will talk about it with you again tomorrow.
明天再來找你商量
I've told you not to come back, right?
我說過不要再來了吧
Bind.
Bin…
I am going to let you off today.
今天我就先放過你
Geez.
真是的
I wish she'd stop coming.
真希望她別再來了
Lady Eris.
艾莉絲大人
You can have me join the Eris Order
回到阿克塞爾後
after I get back to Axel.
要我加入艾莉絲教也行
Please grant me a peaceful life.
拜託妳賜予我安穩的生活
Devil King's Army alert!
魔王軍襲擊警報
The plains near the royal capital are now being occupied by
現在疑似魔王軍的集團
groups thought to be the Devil King's Army.
正在王都附近的平原散開
Knights, please get ready.
騎士團準備出擊
We implore you, all advanced adventurers in the royal capital,
請王都內的各位高級冒險者
to join the fight as well.
也前去參戰
Kazuma, this is bad!
和真 不好了
Quickly get ready.
快點整裝待發
I'm sleeping.
我正在睡覺
Now is not the time to joke around.
現在是開玩笑的時候嗎
The Devil King's Army has appeared!
魔王軍出現了耶
We also have to hurry and join the battle.
我們也得快點去參戰
You are the one joking, right?
在開玩笑的人是妳吧
Please listen to the broadcast properly!
拜託妳好好聽廣播
She said "advanced," right?
她說了"高級"吧
I can barely be considered intermediate.
我勉強只能算是中級
Also,
再說了
this royal capital is full of skilled adventurers everywhere.
這個王都到處都是能幹的冒險者
Even without us, they could win easily.
就算我們不在也能輕鬆打贏
You useless jerk.
你這個傢伙真是…
Forget it, I'll take Aqua and Megumin to the battle.
算了 我帶阿克婭和惠惠去參戰
The lower-level adventurers should simply shiver under their blankets.
低級的冒險者就蓋著棉被發抖吧
I don't want!
不要
Why do I have to go somewhere so dangerous?
為什麼我非得去那種危險的地方
I came to the royal capital to have fun.
我是來王都玩的
I have no desire to fight the Devil King's Army.
我絕對不要去和魔王軍戰鬥
Aqua, don't be so selfish.
阿克婭 別說任性的話
There will never be enough people
能使用恢復魔法的人
who can cast healing spells.
不管有多少都不夠
Look at Megumin, she's full of enthusiasm.
妳看看惠惠 她充滿了幹勁
Darkness, I'm going there first.
達克妮絲 我先去找魔王軍了
Once the battle begins,
一旦開戰了
it will become a melee involving people,
變成參雜著人們的混戰
and I will be unable to use my magic.
就無法使用我的魔法了
I'm going to take the top spot.
我要拔得頭籌
To be more specific, I will defeat the opposition in one fell swoop
準確來說 是用我威力增強的魔法
using my power-enhanced magic.
將對方一網打盡
Wait, Megumin.
等一下 惠惠
Don't talk nonsense.
妳不要胡說八道
Aqua, stop being so contrary.
阿克婭也不要再鬧彆扭了
Geez.
真是的
Kazuma, please think of a solution!
和真 拜託你想想辦法
How long are they going to be loud?
她們依舊吵死人了
It is not worth the risk
何必參加這種戰鬥
to fight in this kind of battle.
讓自己遭遇危險啊
No, wait a minute.
不對 等一下
Making my presence known now
如果這時候重新彰顯我的存在感
could help me live in the city again.
就能再次在城裡生活
Also,
再說了
there are a lot of adventurers in the royal capital who can cheat,
王都有許多擁有作弊能力的冒險者
so I do not see how we could lose.
怎麼想都不可能會輸
Also, we do not have to be unbeatable
而且對付魔王軍
when we face the Devil King's Army.
根本不需要所向無敵
It would be enough for me to
我只要稍微引人注目
just get a little attention.
這樣就夠了
Don't be like that, Darkness.
別這樣 達克妮絲
I have a bad feeling.
我有不好的預感
It's a goddess's intuition.
是女神的直覺
I'll share a sausage with you for breakfast.
早餐的香腸我會分妳一條
Let's talk about it tomorrow.
明天再說吧
When the royal army gets to the battlefield,
抵達戰場的王國軍看到的
they will see the Devil King's Army completely destroyed
將會是淒慘全滅的魔王軍
and the calm magicians leaving the scene.
還有從容離去的魔法師
This is what I want to do.
這就是我想做的事
Now is a good opportunity.
現在是好機會
Let me go!
讓我去啦
Kazuma, I can't handle this!
和真 我做不到
Please control them!
拜託你管管她們兩個
The country is having a hard time.
國家遇到危機
What are you still doing here?
妳們還在這裡做什麼
Okay, let's go.
好了 走吧
Now is the time for us to take the stage.
現在是我們上場的時刻
No!
不要
(Episode 5: A Bad Friend for The Princess)
(第5集 為深閨公主 獻上損友)
Strike!
好球
Hello, today is also a good day.
您好 今天也是好日子
I am Beldia.
我是貝爾迪亞
Let me tell you, no matter how I call…
跟您說 不管我怎麼號召…